# Abdoulkader Haidara

## **CONTACT**

#### **Address**

Moskovskoye Shosse, 25, Dolgoprudny, Moskovskaya oblast (Moscow)

#### E-mail

abdoulkaderhaidaramali@gmail.com

khaidara.a@phystech.edu

#### **PROFILE**

Well qualified Full-Stack Developper Familiar with wide range of programming languages and utilities.

Solid knowledge in mathematics as am a computer science student, worked with most of popular data structures and implemented well known algorithms.

Knowledgeable of backend and frontend developments requirements.

Collaborative teammate with easy team integration and excellent team working abilities.

## **EXPERIENCE**

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER, HACKBIO - 2021 - PRESENT

As a full stack developer at <u>thehackbio.com</u> I built and maintain all HackBio's applications which include the admin application, the client application, the internship application, the static home website.

I work principally with Typescript for both backend and frontend and use the following frameworks and libraries: **Reactjs, Nextjs, Nestjs, Mui etc** 

I work with Postgres Database in the Backend for storing data.

FREELANCE MOBILE AND WEB DEVELOPER — 2020 - PRESENT

As a freelance mobile and web developer, I have been working with some people on personal projects.

## Studappy (<a href="https://www.studappy.com/">https://www.studappy.com/</a>):

I built a part of studappy's website on Wix platform.

PERSONAL/STUDENT PROJECTS

- Reddit Clone Api using Python & FASTApi & Docker & Kubernetes (https://github.com/teyalite/reddit-clone)
- Real time chat application for desktop using Qt in C++ (<a href="https://github.com/">https://github.com/</a>
  teyalite/NetworkChat)
- Client-Server multithreading downloader in Golang and Javascript (<a href="https://github.com/teyalite/client-sever-multithreading-downloader">https://github.com/teyalite/client-sever-multithreading-downloader</a>)
- Implementation of Some data structures and Algorithms (<a href="https://github.com/">https://github.com/</a> teyalite/Data-Structures-Algorithms).

### **EDUCATION**

- Computer Science Bachelor degree at Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology(MIPT) 2020 - Present
- Preparatory Course at Higher School of Economics(HSE) in Moscow 2019 2020

## **SKILLS**

- Critical thinking (Very Good)
- Data Structures and Algorithms (Excellent)
- SQL (Excellent)
- Javascript / Typescript(Excellent)
- PHP (Excellent)
- Http (Excellent)
- Java (Very Good)
- Python (Very Good)
- C++ (Very Good)
- Flutter framework for cross platform mobile development (Very Good)
- Git (Very Good)
- HTML / CSS (Excellent)